BOLU ADETIFA

Phone: +234(0) 810-555-1713 | Email: boluadetifa@gmail.com
LinkedIn: boluadetifa@gmail.com
LinkedIn: boluadetifa@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A Computer Science student with three years of experience in building full stack software with modern technologies mainly in backend engineering. With interest in building software products to provide value for people. I currently use JavaScript and Golang.

EXPERIENCE

April 2022 - Present

Software Engineer, Applistructure

- Architected and built a financing platform
- Integrated payment processors to handle payment within the platform
- Integrated real time messaging
- Technologies used: Typescript, Node, Express, React, SQL, Next, Redis and Mongodb

November 2021 - April 2022

Software Engineering Intern, COMSIT

- Lead and Worked with teammates to create a website for filling APER forms which increased entry speed by over 100%
- Maintained and tested a project in production with which reduced the bugs on the application by 70%
- Created technical documents for projects in production
- Technologies used: Typescript, Java, Node, React, SQL, Next and Mongodb

July 2020 - July 2021

Software Engineering Intern, Hamoye

- Worked with data sets, cleaned, analyzed them and created ML models
- Technologies used: Python, Django, Pandas, Anaconda, Numpy, Matplotlib and PowerBI

PROJECTS

September 2022 – October 2022

Amor, https://github.com/Bolu1/amor-server

- Created a productivity application with golang
- Implemented a feature that creates emails for users and sends mails to other users with the application
- Implemented a cloud storage system with golang file system where users can upload, store and retrieve their files
- Implemented a video call feature where users can create video meetings and invite other users
- Technologies used: Golang, Gin, Mongodb, WebRTC

April 2022 - May 2022

Gbese, https://gbese-client.vercel.app

Code: https://github.com/Bolu1/gbese-server

- Created a savings web app where users can join and keep money in their wallets
- Integrated a payment processor which users can use to deposit money from their banks
- Implemented a system that allows users to send money to one another within the app
- Implemented a feature the users can use to send money to any bank account in Nigeria
- Implemented a mailing system that sends user's transfer and account information
- Wrote unit testing using pactum JS
- Technologies used: Node Js, Typescript, Nest JS, Next JS, Kafka, Redis, Docker, MySql,
 Pactum JS

March 2022 - March 2022

NoWalls, https://nowalls.vercel.app

Code: https://github.com/Bolu1/no-walls-server

- Created an online classroom for teachers and students
- Implemented file upload and download
- Implemented assignment and submission functionality
- Implemented a feature that allows users to join or create a class
- Technologies used: Graphql, Typescript, Node JS, Express JS, Next JS, Mongodb

CERTIFICATION

SEPTEMBER 2020

Applied Machine Learning in Python, Coursera

Credential: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/YWH2WXF4EXWE

SKILLS

<u>Languages/Frameworks</u>: Typescript, Golang, Java, Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, React.js, Next.js <u>Software/Tools</u>: SQL, GraphQL, Git, Redis, Docker, Kafka, MongoDB, AWS (EKS, ECS, S3, EC2)

EDUCATION

2018 - PRESENT

University of Ilorin, Nigeria

B.S.c, Computer Science

Course work: Distributed Systems, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Parallel Programming, Software Engineering, Algorithm & Data Structures.